CV - MICHAEL TILLCOCK

Email - michael@golfclublist.com

GitHub - https://github.com/gclcodeguy

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/michaeltillcock/

Hyperion Dev Profile - https://www.hyperiondev.com/portfolio/116795/

Personal Profile

Michael has a unique professional background with over 8 years working in risk, technology and Artificial Intelligence (AI) as a Management Consultant and a more recent transition into full stack web development as a founder of his own SaaS business.

Michael founded https://golfclublist.com, a golf information comparison website and won a scholarship onto a Full Stack Web Developer bootcamp which had over 20,000 applicants. On the bootcamp Michael learned full stack development using the MERN stack and utilised those skills, supplemented by self-study, to build golfclublist.

Michael's previous experience was as risk professional and management consultant for both KPMG and BCS Consulting, part of Accenture. Michael worked primarily on risk, operating model and AI programmes for financial services clients including HSBC, Santander, First Abu Dhabi Bank, Santander, Royal Bank of Scotland and Barclays.

Career History

- Founder Golfclublist Ltd (Oct 2023 Present)
 - Built a dynamic full stack golf information comparison website using HTML, CSS, Bootstap5, Javascript and various api integrations including CloudTables and postcode.io
 - Social media accounts for the business have more 5.5m views and an associate Golf podcast has over 1000 unique listens and over 500k clip views
 - The website is planned to launch in 1Q 2023
- Senior Manager, BCS Consulting part of Accenture (upon final integration with Accenture in April 2022)
- Four promotions from Associate Consultant to Senior Manager (March 2016 May 2022)
- Recruited onto an internal future leaders' programme and a talent retention bonus scheme post integration with Accenture

Universal Bank – Al Transaction Monitoring (FinCrime) Solution Programme (August 2020 – May 2022)

- Led a team of 6 consultants and up top 5 other Business Analysts (BA) on all BA design streams; securing four consecutive extensions providing over £2m in revenue and extending the BCS team into new workstreams, despite extreme restrictions on external spend in the Risk and Compliance function
- Documented the DRA Control Framework and Operating Model following several months of design iterations, culminating in Group Financial Crime Executive Committee (ExCo) approval
- Wrote a 'Global Model Design Options' paper combining the model performance results from analytical experiments with the wider business implications of the model options into one coherent paper to guide decision makers
- Communicated how newly identified operational risks would be mitigated after the DRA went live, to C-Suite stakeholders including the Group MLRO, Group AML Risk Steward, UK Chief Compliance Officer etc.

Universal Bank - Information, Technology & Cyber Security Risk Programme (November 2019 - August 2020)

 Led the consulting team of nine and a wider working group of over a hundred stakeholders to deliver a programme of work to implement the bank's new Information, Technology and Cyber Security (ITCS) Control Library across Group Technology, to meet a critical, Prudential Regulation Authority (PRA) commitment

UK Branch of a Middle Eastern Bank - Target Operating Model project (April 2019 - August 2019)

- Led the design and documentation of the UK Branch's Target Operating Model, commend by the UK CEO Universal Bank Group Operational Risk (January 2018 March 2019)
- Led an Assurance Proof of Concept to pilot the new assurance guidance and system functionality in IBM OpenPages Universal Bank Risk Policy Management Process Design (July 2017 December 2017)
- Led a project to improve policy management in the Retail Bank

Universal Bank – Retail Bank Conduct Risk Programme (April 2016 – June 2017)

- Led the delivery, embedding and assurance of Conduct Gap Closure for over ten markets across Europe and LAM
- Senior Associate, KPMG Advisory, Operational Transformation (October 2013 March 2016)

Performed Business Analyst and junior Project Manager roles on a Financial Crime Transformation Programme, a Product Simplification Programme and a Skilled Person (SP166) Review of IRD misselling.

Education

2022 - 2023**Hyperion Dev** 4-month Bootcamp – Full Stack Web Development 2013 - 2015**BPP University** Finance Qualification - CIMA Management Level Exams Passed (All 1st time passes) 2008 - 2011**Durham University** Degree: 2.1 Economics BA (Honours) 12,000-word dissertation which used regression analysis to analyse economic growth and inequality in Chile since 1970, was requested for display as one of the top Economics dissertations of the year 2006 - 2008**Nottingham High School** A Level: 3 A's (Economics, Maths and Geography), AS Level: 2 As (History, General Studies)

2000 - 2006**Nottingham High School**

GCSE: 9 A*'s (Maths, History, Geography, English Literature, French, German, Chemistry, Biology, Physics) and

1 A (English Language)

Web Development Skills

- Frontend development with HTML5, CSS, Tailwind UI and Bootstrap5
- Software development in JavaScript
- Static and dynamic web development
- Object-oriented programming
- **Functional programming**
- Single-page application development with libraries such as React.js
- Source version control
- Web API integration

Personal Interests

- I am a keen club golfer and enjoy social football using the Footy Addicts app
- I enjoy spending time with my wife and our energetic miniature golden doodle, Ralphie
- I founded an annual team golf competition for Durham University alumni 'The Beder Cup' which recently had its tenth instalment in the Lake District, and has had over 40 different attendees over the last decade
- I have an interest in Latin America having lived in Chile for 5 months during a post university gap year where I worked as an English Language Assistant in 2013
- Technology, web development and AI

References available on request